<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meta on Neyas Guruswamy's Personal Wiki</title><link>https://neyasg.github.io/personal-wiki/tags/meta/</link><description>Recent content in Meta on Neyas Guruswamy's Personal Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neyasg.github.io/personal-wiki/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Pro Gamer to Data Engineer</title><link>https://neyasg.github.io/personal-wiki/p/from-pro-gamer-to-data-engineer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neyasg.github.io/personal-wiki/p/from-pro-gamer-to-data-engineer/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://neyasg.github.io/personal-wiki/p/from-pro-gamer-to-data-engineer/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post From Pro Gamer to Data Engineer" />&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Welcome to my personal blog! This space serves as my personal wiki and progress tracker as I dive into the world of Data Engineering, and software development. Stay a while and listen!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="a-little-bit-about-me">A little bit about me
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Graduating in Mechanical Engineering from Heriot-Watt University in 2018 may lead some down the path of industry, working their way to a chartered engineering certification and paving the way for a career in companies building bridges, cars, or machines. My journey however started off quite differently, with a stint in the professional video game industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Playing for an eSports team for a living was quite the unorthodox career, but it taught me a few things which I found useful now I&amp;rsquo;m working in what I would previously call a &amp;ldquo;boring&amp;rdquo; 9-5. The non-stop competitive gauntlet I was immersed in daily solved a lot of what I was lacking in University. Drive. So after &lt;em>retiring&lt;/em> from competitive eSports and stumbling into the world of data engineering by almost chance (A story for another post), I find myself using that drive to tickle the problem solving part of my brain, building data pipelines, untangling strange behaviour and solving data puzzles.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-in-the-pipeline">What&amp;rsquo;s in the pipeline?
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Expect posts covering topics on &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.databricks.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Databricks&lt;/a>, &lt;a class="link" href="https://aws.amazon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>AWS&lt;/a>, &lt;a class="link" href="https://spark.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Apache Spark&lt;/a>, &lt;a class="link" href="https://developer.hashicorp.com/terraform" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Terraform&lt;/a> and any other tools and platforms I encounter as I build up my experience. I&amp;rsquo;ll be documenting my personal projects, challenges and all, the first of which is a simulated music streaming application (think Spotify) ingesting data in real time using Apache Kafka and Spark structured streaming to create a live dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For anyone stumbling on this blog, whether that be fellow Data Engineers and devs, or LinkedIn connections or if I&amp;rsquo;m lucky, potential employers, thank you for reading, and I hope you&amp;rsquo;ve found something useful while here!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>